

# **AMIR ALI**

I've always been interested in technology and the exponentially growing reliance society has on it now and will have in the future. So, I thought I should 'Futureproof' myself and learn the skills needed to contribute and hopefully build useful products and applications that will help people (and society) to unlock value in their daily life and become more efficient. I am also deeply fascinated by the mirage of technology, finance and the promise of trustless contracts, and the implications that holds for the future. That's to say nothing of AI and ML. Ultimately, I am starting on this journey from a traditional engineering background and look forward to the next 2-3 years of upskilling myself, increasing my coding pedigree and contributing value to the company and the workplace culture.

## **SUMMARY**

Currently a tech trainee at futureproof learning the curriculum for full stack development. It has been a rollercoaster of a journey so far and we're only a few weeks in. I can't wait to see where I am at the end of the 13 weeks, never mind 2, 3, 5 or 10 years down the line!

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Futureproof | Tech Trainee | April 2022 - July 2022

- 13-week bootcamp covering the main areas of web development, including JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Databases, and Python.
- Recently completed a 1-week group project using React to create a trivia uiz, using Jest and Enzyme to test.

#### Hibiscus Petroleum | Project Economist | Oct 2019 - Mar 2021

- Reported to COO, modelled and assessed economic viability of a North Sea billion-dollar project, including stress-testing 1000's of scenarios
- Interfaced with internal and external partners including regulatory authorities.
- Initially started as an intern then made full-time employee continuing with my Project Economist role, whilst also contributing to the Drilling Engineering department.

#### Sporting Solutions | Traffic Mgmt. Supervisor | July - Oct 2014

- Managed all transport routes around SECC and Hydro Arenas.
- Promotion from small team leader to supervisor of team of 41.

#### **EDUCATION**

Heriot Watt University | Sept 2018 - Sept 2019

MSc Petroleum Engineering

University of Leeds | Oct 2015 - July 2018

BEng Petroleum Engineering – First Class Honors

## **FIND OUT MORE**

**(7)** 

<u>GitHub</u>

in

<u>LinkedIn</u>

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Command Line Interface

Git/GitHub

HTML/CSS

JavaScript

**Python** 

**Bootstrap** 

## PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Leadership

**Teamwork** 

Communication